<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Magda Kowalska</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Magda Kowalska</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 17:28:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DIY: How to check that global warming is real</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/diy-how-to-check-that-global-warming-is-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 17:28:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/diy-how-to-check-that-global-warming-is-real/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&#xA;  .row {&#xA;    display: flex;&#xA;    justify-content: space-between;&#xA;  }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never done any data science but today I had a chance to watch a few talks from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.compsust.net/compsust-2020/&#34;&gt;2020 Computational Sustainability Conference&lt;/a&gt; and felt inspired to checkout the Python pandas package and see what I can do with it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking for interesting sources of data I stumbled upon the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration website that allows you to download (for free!) historical weather data (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/cdo-web/search&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/cdo-web/search&#34;&gt;https://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/cdo-web/search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) for many different locations around the world. Some of the data sets go as far as early XX century. How cool!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FemEng in Rwanda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project_fem_eng_rwanda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 09:43:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project_fem_eng_rwanda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/rwanda5.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2015 I lucky to be invited by the FemEng (Female Engineering) society from University of Glasgow to help them organise their first edition of &amp;ldquo;FemEng in Rwanda&amp;rdquo; project. We collaborated with students from University of Rwanda in Kigali and organised workshops about science and engineering for school girls in the Kigali area.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/rwanda3.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the mix of aspiring engineers specialising in different fields we created workshops about Biomedical, Mechanical, Civil, Aerospace and Software engineering. As well as Product Design and Renewable Energy and Water engineering. As the only software engineer on the team, I was responsible for running the Software Engineering workshop. Thanks to the University of Rwanda we were able to run the workshop at the computer science lab on campus. I decided to give a short presentation about computer science, programming and different career paths. Then a quick intro to Scratch programming followed by a hands on programming session using Scratch. It was incredible to see the girls being excited about their programs running and doing different things on the screen as well as playing sounds. Some of the participants of the workshop never used a computer before and it was incredible to see how quickly they could pick up Scratch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teleport</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project_teleport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 09:43:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project_teleport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/teleport.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As my final year university project I decided to develop a mobile app. It&amp;rsquo;s a location based photo sharing app that I called Teleport. The project aimed at researching a new way through which people could communicate with each other. Taking into account all the existing photo sharing and communication apps, I came up with a novel idea where the users can request content from anywhere on a map and receive pictures of the locations that are only visible for a limited amount of time. Basically, the app allows you to &lt;span style=&#39;font-style: italic&#39;&gt;teleport&lt;/span&gt; wherever you want using your phone and the help of community that uses the app.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My campervan conversion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-campervan-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 17:28:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-campervan-conversion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&#xA;  .row {&#xA;    display: flex;&#xA;    justify-content: space-between;&#xA;  }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In June 2017 I got a 2010 Opel Movano with the idea of turning it into a mobile home and moving into and driving it all across Europe(and possibly beyond). Having spent a big chunk of my childhood traveling in a campervan with my family, it seemed like an obvious thing to do. After an initial first month of working on the van I didn&amp;rsquo;t get very far but was super stoked on the idea. In the end it led me to the decision of quitting my job at Morgan Stanley, moving back home to Poland and focusing entirely on the van. My friend came over and stayed for over a month, helping me out throughout the process.&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
