<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Magda Kowalska</title>
    <link>https://kowalsska.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Magda Kowalska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 21:09:48 -1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kowalsska.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FemEng in Rwanda</title>
      <link>https://kowalsska.github.io/projects/project_fem_eng_rwanda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 09:43:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kowalsska.github.io/projects/project_fem_eng_rwanda/</guid>
      <description>In 2015 I lucky to be invited by the FemEng (Female Engineering) society from University of Glasgow to help them organise their first edition of &amp;ldquo;FemEng in Rwanda&amp;rdquo; project. We collaborated with students from University of Rwanda in Kigali and organised workshops about science and engineering for school girls in the Kigali area.
With the mix of aspiring engineers specialising in different fields we created workshops about Biomedical, Mechanical, Civil, Aerospace and Software engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teleport</title>
      <link>https://kowalsska.github.io/projects/project_teleport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 09:43:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kowalsska.github.io/projects/project_teleport/</guid>
      <description>As my final year university project I decided to develop a mobile app. It&amp;rsquo;s a location based photo sharing app that I called Teleport. The project aimed at researching a new way through which people could communicate with each other. Taking into account all the existing photo sharing and communication apps, I came up with a novel idea where the users can request content from anywhere on a map and receive pictures of the locations that are only visible for a limited amount of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My campervan conversion</title>
      <link>https://kowalsska.github.io/blog/my-campervan-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 17:28:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kowalsska.github.io/blog/my-campervan-conversion/</guid>
      <description>.row { display: flex; justify-content: space-between; }  In June 2017 I got a 2010 Opel Movano with the idea of turning it into a mobile home and moving into and driving it all across Europe(and possibly beyond). Having spent a big chunk of my childhood traveling in a campervan with my family, it seemed like an obvious thing to do. After an initial first month of working on the van I didn&amp;rsquo;t get very far but was super stoked on the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
